Guide to the William McFee Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William McFee collection
1862-1966
1900-1966
GEN MSS 991
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
39.91
(107 Boxes) + 1 art
The William McFee Collection contains correspondence between McFee and literary colleagues, publishers, friends, and family; third-party correspondence concerning McFee, his family, and his friendship with James T. Babb; autograph manuscript or typescript drafts for most of McFee's novels, and for short stories, essays, books reviews, and poems; autograph manuscript diaries, 1911-1963; writings of others, including Margery Allingham and Beatrice Allender McFee; photographs of McFee and others; drawings of McFee and illustrations for his writings by Arthur J. Elder and others; a bronze bust of McFee by Jason Sturm (Yale 1922); scrapbooks containing clippings about McFee, reviews of his writings, photographs, and ephemera; other clippings about McFee; personal papers, mostly concerning McFee's family or his work as a marine engineer; correspondence relating to Babb's collecting of books and manuscripts by McFee, and research materials and drafts for A Bibliography of the Writings of William McFee; audiotapes relating to McFee's 75th birthday in 1956; and films and videocassettes of McFee and his family. Major correspondents include Margery Allingham, other members of the Allingham family, James T. Babb, Van Wyck Brooks, Arthur J. Elder, George T. Keating, Beatrice Allender McFee, other members of the McFee family, Byrne Marconnier, Harry E. Maule, Christopher Morley, Dudley Nichols, and Frank Swinnerton.
McFee, William, 1881-1966
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: Acquisitions, 1948-1972 and 1983; and Acquisitions, 1979-2002.
William McFee (1881-1966)
William McFee (Yale 1936 MA honorary), marine engineer, and author of maritime fiction. McFee was born in London, moved to the United States in 1911, and became an American citizen in 1925, settling in Roxbury, Connecticut. He served as an engineer in the British navy during World War I, and for the United Fruit Company and other merchant ships, 1906-1924. McFee wrote maritime novels, short stories, and essays, and reviewed books about the sea for the The Sun (New York) and the New York Times. He was married to Pauline Khondoff, 1920-1932, and novelist Beatrice Allender, 1932-1952; he later married Dorothy North, and was stepfather of North's son Richard McFee.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 93-95: Restricted until 2033 September 24. For more information, consult the appropriate curator.
Box 92 (reel-to-reel audiotapes) and box 103 (16mm films): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 106-107: Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James T. Babb, (Yale 1924), 1952-1968, gift of Harry E. Maule, 1954 and 1970, and gift of Margaret Bradley Babb, 1983; and acquired from other donors and vendors, 1948-2002, as indicated in subseries and folder notes. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Related Materials
McFee, William. Miscellaneous pamphlets and other ephemera by and about William McFee (Iq M167 +1).
Other books owned by McFee may be found in the online catalog by searching "McFee, William" as a special collections subject or "Iq M167" as a local call number.
James T. Babb (1899-1968)
James T. Babb (Yale 1924), book and manuscript collector; Yale University Librarian, 1943-1965. Babb collected books and manuscripts by William McFee and was the author of A Bibliography of the Writings of William McFee (Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1931).
Scope and Contents
The William McFee Collection contains correspondence between McFee and literary colleagues, publishers, friends, and family; third-party correspondence concerning McFee, his family, and his friendship with James T. Babb; autograph manuscript or typescript drafts for most of McFee's novels, and for short stories, essays, books reviews, and poems; autograph manuscript diaries, 1911-1963; writings of others, including Margery Allingham and Beatrice Allender McFee; photographs of McFee and others; drawings of McFee and illustrations for his writings by Arthur J. Elder and others; a bronze bust of McFee by Jason Sturm (Yale 1922); scrapbooks containing clippings about McFee, reviews of his writings, photographs, and ephemera; other clippings about McFee; personal papers, mostly concerning McFee's family or his work as a marine engineer; correspondence relating to Babb's collecting of books and manuscripts by McFee, and research materials and drafts for A Bibliography of the Writings of William McFee; audiotapes relating to McFee's 75th birthday in 1956; and films and videocassettes of McFee and his family. Major correspondents include Margery Allingham, other members of the Allingham family, James T. Babb, Van Wyck Brooks, Arthur J. Elder, George T. Keating, Beatrice Allender McFee, other members of the McFee family, Byrne Marconnier, Harry E. Maule, Christopher Morley, Dudley Nichols, and Frank Swinnerton.
Adventure stories, American; Adventure stories, English; Authors, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; Book collecting -- United States; Book collectors -- United States; English literature -- 20th Century; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; Marine engineering -- Great Britain; Marine engineers -- Great Britain; Seafaring life in literature; Audiotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Busts (figures) -- United States -- 20th Century; Diaries -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Diaries -- United States -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- United States -- 20th Century; Motion pictures (visual works) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Sculpture (visual work) -- United States -- 20th Century; Videotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Marine engineers -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Allingham, Margery, 1904-1966; Allingham family; Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968; Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968 ( Bibliography of the writings of William McFee); Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963; Elder, Arthur J., 1874-; Keating, George T., 1892-; McFee, Beatrice Allender; McFee, William, 1881-1966; McPhee family; Marconnier, Byrne; Maule, Harry E. (Harry Edward), 1886-; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957; Nichols, Dudley, 1895-1960; Sturm, Jason; Swinnerton, Frank, 1884-1982; Great Britain. Royal Navy; United Fruit Company. Engineering Department
- Acquisitions, 1948-1972 and 1983, 1862-1966, undated; 36.91; (98 boxes) + 1 art
  Arrangement
  Organized into seven subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Writings of Others, Printed Material, Personal Papers, Photographs and Other Visual Materials, and James T. Babb Research Materials.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains materials acquired from James T. Babb, Harry E. Maule, and other sources through 1972, and from Margaret Bradley Babb, 1983. These materials were partially integrated prior to 2014.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 92 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence, 1889-1966, undated
    Related Materials
    Additional correspondence is in the Writings and James T. Babb Research Materials subseries.
    Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, with most large groups of letters from McFee noted in folder titles. Letters concern McFee's writing; his relationships with literary colleagues, friends, and family; and the United Fruit Company and other marine engineering work. Some letters include writings, publisher contracts, royalty statements, or photographs. Third-party correspondence contains letters about McFee between James T. Babb, members of the McFee family, and friends of McFee.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent, followed by third-party correspondence and unsorted correspondence.
    - Abramson, Ben (from McFee), 1931-1941 (Box 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Gift of Philip D. Sang, 1955
    - Adamic, Louis (from McFee), [1939], undated (Box 1)
      In response to a questionnaire from Adamic addressed "To Distinguished Immigrant Americans"
    - Allender, Inez, 1956-1962 (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Emily Jane, 1919-1937, undated (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Emily Jane (from McFee), 1916-1919, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Herbert John, 1918-1928 (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Herbert John (from McFee), 1906-1933; 6 (Box 1)
    - Allingham, Margery, 1923-1937 (Box 2)
      Accompanied by a program for a music performance for which Margery Allingham wrote several pieces and designed costumes
    - Allingham, Margery (from McFee), 1922 July 10 (Box 2)
    - Allingham, Margery, 1954-1964 (Box 2)
    - Allingham, Phillip (from McFee), 1916 October 20 (Box 2)
    - Allingham family, 1913-1960; 3 (Box 2)
    - The American Mercury, 1926-1927 (Box 2)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1917-1952 (Box 2)
    - Babb, James T., 1928-1934; 6 (Box 2)
    - Babb, James T., 1935-1949, 1965; 9 (Box 3)
    - Babb, James T., 1956-1965; 2 (Box 4)
    - Baines, Jocelyn (from McFee), 1961 January 10 (Box 4)
      Gift of Jocelyn Baines, 1972
      About Joseph Conrad
    - Beard, Mary R., 1946-1948 (Box 4)
    - Becker, Belle (from McFee), 1948 July 29 (Box 4)
      Gift of Harry E. Maule, 1954
      Belle Becker was Harry E. Maule's secretary
    - Benét, William Rose, 1929-1944 (Box 4)
    - Bissell, Richard (to James T. Babb), 1965 October 11 (Box 4)
    - Bone, David W., 1948-1960 (Box 4)
    - Bone, James, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Boyd, Ernest, 1931-1933 (Box 4)
    - Brooks, Eleanor, 1944, undated (Box 4)
    - Brooks, Gladys, 1948, undated (Box 4)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1941 December 8 (Box 4)
      Removed from: Brooks, Van Wyck. Opinions of Oliver Allston (New York: E. P. Dutton, 1941)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1936-1960; 2 (Box 4)
    - Burton, Ralph J., 1964, undated (Box 4)
      Gift of Ralph J. Burton, 1968
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1913, 1923 (Box 4)
    - Colcord, Lincoln, 1923-1936 (Box 4)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1944-1964 (Box 4)
    - Curtiss, Ursula Reilly, 1960-1963 (Box 5)
    - Dorman, Sonya, 1955 April 22 (Box 5)
      Gift of William McFee, 1955
    - Dorman, Sonya (from McFee), 1955 April 27 (Box 5)
    - Doubleday, Page & Company, 1917-1965; 4 (Box 5)
    - Elder, Arthur J., 1902-1916; 4 (Box 5)
    - Elder, Arthur J., 1917-1944; 8 (Box 6)
    - Elder family, 1918-1940 (Box 6)
      Includes correspondence with Arthur J. Elder's wife, nicknamed "Bill"
    - Faber & Faber, 1928-1935 (Box 7)
    - Fink, Dorothy, undated (Box 7)
    - Grant, Gordon, 1939-1941 (Box 7)
    - Gunther, John, 1925-1949 (Box 7)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1919-1928 (Box 7)
    - Household, Geoffrey, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
    - Jacques Chambrun, Inc., 1958-1961 (Box 7)
    - John Lane The Bodley Head Limited, 1924-1931 (Box 7)
    - Jonker, T., 1915-1926 (Box 7)
    - Kappel, Philip, 1950 March 21 (Box 7)
      Removed from: Kappel, Philip. Louisiana Gallery: the River Country and New Orleans (New York: Putman, c1950)
    - Kauser, Alice, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Keating, George T., 1958 July 18 (Box 7)
    - Keating, George T., 1929-1966 (Box 7)
    - Keating, George T., and Harriet Keating (Box 7)
    - Kieran, John, 1938-1959 (Box 7)
    - Kilmer, Joyce, 1916 March 6 (Box 7)
    - Lozell, Clifford C. (from McFee), 1961-1963 (Box 7)
      Gift of Clifford C. Lozell, 1968
    - McCoy, Samuel Duff, 1956-1964 (Box 7)
    - McFee, Beatrice Allender, 1952-1953; 3 (Box 8)
      Letters to William Mcfee and Beatrice Allender McFee during her last illness and after her death
    - McFee, John Henry, and Hilda McFee, 1896-1936 (Box 8)
    - McFee family, 1889-1935; 2 (Box 8)
    - McFee, Pauline Khondoff, 1920 (Box 8)
    - Marconnier, Byrne (from McFee), 1927-1939; 7 (Box 8)
      Gift of Walter Beinecke, 1952
      Accompanied by: review by McFee of Donn Byrne's Field of Honor (with letter, 1929 September 12); Blodgett, Glenn Walton, letter to McFee, 1929 January 1, and copy of a poem by Blodgett (with letter, 1930 January 9); memorandum (wth letter, 1935 April 19); Morely, Christopher, Saturday Review article; and other clippings
    - Marconnier, Byrne, 1927, 1929 (Box 8)
    - Marconnier, Emily (from McFee), 1930-1931 (Box 8)
    - Maule, Edna J. O'Dell (from McFee), 1947 (Box 9)
      Accompanied by a photograph of Richard McFee and Anne McFee, 1947 June 16 (with letter, 1947 July 16)
    - Maule, Harry E., 1943-1949 (Box 9)
      See also: Doubleday, Page & Company
      Gift of James T. Babb, 1953, and Harry E. Maule, 1954
    - Maule, Harry E. (from McFee), 1919-1952; 8 (Box 9)
      Gift of Harry E. Maule, 1948, 1949, and 1954
      Accompanied by a photograph of McFee; "How I Came to Write 'Race,'" by McFee, autograph manuscript; a note from F. P. Adams, typescript copy; and quotations from McFee's Watch Below, typescript copy
    - Maule, Harry E., 1934-1940; 4 (Box 10)
    - Maule, Harry E. (from McFee), 1929-1952; 3 (Box 10)
      Gift of Harry E. Maule, 1970
    - Maule, Harry E., 1941-1945; 11 (Box 11)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1931 (Box 12)
      Removed from letters from McFee to Dudley Nichols, 1931 June 25 and July 3
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), undated (Box 12)
    - Molloy, Robert, 1958 (Box 12)
    - Molloy, Robert, undated (Box 12)
    - Morley, Christopher, 1949 January-May (Box 12)
    - Morley, Christopher (from McFee). Photocopies, 1917-1922 (Box 12)
    - Morley, Christopher, 1916-1937; 2 (Box 12)
    - Neilson, John, 1958 February-March (Box 12)
      With enclosures: Cooper, F. G., "The Story of Conrad's Lord Jim " ( The Annual Dog Watch, no. 10, 1953); and speech by Neilson, typescript carbon
    - Nichols, Dudley, 1920-1957; 2 (Box 12)
      Accompanied by: "JB," short story by Nichols, typescript
    - Nichols, Dudley (from McFee), 1958-1959, undated; 2 (Box 13)
    - Nichols, Dudley (from McFee), 1931-1954; 6 (Box 13)
      Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1949, 1953, 1954, 1956, and 1957
      Accompanied by: review of Bromfield, Louis, It Takes All Kinds, by McFee, autograph manuscript (with letter, 1940 January 21); review of Wolfe, Thomas, You Can't Go Home Again (with letter, 1944 September 18); Star of Scotland, synopsis, typescript carbon (with letter, 1944 December 13); postcard from "Mrs. J. M. D. Warnke" to the New York Post, copy (with letter, 1950 August 18); photograph of Beatrice Allender McFee's mother (with letter, 1953 January 11); photograph of McFee and his daughter-in-law, Anne McFee (with letter, 1953 November 12); and letter from Charlton Ogburn to "Miss Alexander," the New York Herald Tribune, copy (with letter, 1954 January 3)
    - Nichols, Dudley (from McFee), 1954-1959; 5 (Box 14)
      Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1949, 1953, 1954, 1956, 1957, and 1959
    - Nichols, Esta, 1960 (Box 14)
    - Nichols, Esta (from McFee), 1951-1957 (Box 14)
      Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1954 and 1957
    - Nichols, Esta, 1964, undated (Box 14)
    - Niven, Frederick, 1925-1926 (Box 14)
    - Noble, Susan Ames, 1956 February 29 (Box 14)
      Accompanied by a brief note by McFee, typescript
      Removed from Swinnerton Frank, A London Bookman (London: Martin Secker, 1930)
    - O'Hara, John, 1946-1957 (Box 14)
    - Paine, Ralph Delahaye, 1922-1924 (Box 14)
    - Post, Mary Brinker, 1959-1965 (Box 14)
    - Potts, Robert A., 1938-1943 (Box 14)
    - Riesenberg, Felix, 1927-1931 (Box 14)
    - Sawyer, Roland (from McFee), 1949-1960 (Box 14)
      Gift of Roland Sawyer, 1961
    - Saxton, Eugene F. (from McFee), 1933-1938 (Box 15)
      Gift of Harper & Row, Publishers, 1963
    - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1925-1946 (Box 15)
    - Shakespeare Fellowship, 1956-1963; 4 (Box 15)
    - Shields, Louis Gerald (from McFee), 1932 March 28 (Box 15)
      Gift of Mrs. John Archer Gee, 1968
      In response to a request from the Yale Daily News about "the literary life and the chances of college men therein"
    - Simon, Richard S. (from McFee), 1930 February 24 (Box 15)
      Introducing Byrne Marconnier
    - Smith, Henry Justin (from McFee), undated (Box 15)
    - Smith, Tom, 1956-1964 (Box 15)
    - Steinberg, Herbert E., 1953-1964; 3 (Box 15)
      Gift of Herbert E. Steinberg, 1966
      Includes "Prentice Days," poem by McFee, autograph manuscript
    - Stokes, Frederick A., 1934 May 28 (Box 15)
      Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1954
      Confirming McFee's order for a copy of Philip Allingham's Cheapjack, and requesting McFee to write for the book jacket
    - The Sun (New York, N.Y.), 1930-1942 (Box 15)
    - Swinnerton, Frank (from McFee), 1924-1963; 5 (Box 16)
      Gift of Frank Swinnerton, 1964
    - Swinnerton, Frank, 1924-1962; 2 (Box 16)
      Letter dated 1925 August 28: gift of George M. Adams, 1942; removed from Swinnerton, Frank, George Gissing: A Critical Study (New York, c1923)
      Includes letters from "Olivia," Swinnerton's daughter, no year, August 19, from "Mary," his wife, 1948 August 19; and from Edward Weeks's secretary and from Weeks to Swinnerton, copy, 1946 November 7-8; and a press release, Doubleday, 1959 February 8
    - Swinnerton, Frank, 1964-1965; 2 (Box 16)
    - Taylor, Warner (from McFee), 1931 October 15 (Box 16)
      About McFee's views on prose style
    - Tomlinson, Henry Major, 1932-1935 (Box 16)
    - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1923 November 15 (Box 16)
      Acknowledging receipt of McFee's short story "Race" by the American Play Company
    - United Fruit Company, 1920-1949; 2 (Box 16)
    - Walpole, Hugh, 1928-1935 (Box 16)
    - Watt, A. P., 1913-1965; 4 (Box 17)
    - White, Katherine A., 1930-1931 (Box 17)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1941-1958 (Box 17)
    - Unidentified, 1937 April 5 (Box 17)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 17)
      Source of acquisition unidentified
    - Third-Party Correspondence
      - Allingham, Emily Jane (to James T. Babb), 1937 November 10 (Box 17)
        Formerly enclosed with letter to McFee from Margery Allingham, 1937 November 10
      - Allingham, Herbert John (to Arthur J. Elder), 1912-1919 (Box 17)
        Letter dated 1912 May 14 mentions a weekend visit by McFee
      - Cragg, Alliston (to Dudley Nichols), 1953 December 16 (Box 17)
        Accompanied by "Wage, Price, Profit Problems," mimeograph copy
      - Elder, Arthur J. (to Christopher Morley), [1919?] October 21 (Box 17)
        Gift of Thomas W. Streeter, 1951
      - Elder, Arthur J., 1931 (Box 17)
      - McFee, Beatrice Allender, 1932-1945 (Box 17)
      - McFee, Richard, undated (Box 17)
      - MacKenna, Kenneth (to Dudley Nichols), 1953 June 26 (Box 17)
      - Nichols, Dudley (to James T. Babb), 1953-1958 (Box 17)
        Accompanied by letters, typescript carbon, from Babb to Nichols, 1957 November 18, and from Babb's secretary to Nichols, 1957 November 13
      - 75th birthday correspondence, 1955-1956; 4 (Box 17)
    - Unsorted, outgoing, 1925-1931; 9 (Box 18)
    - Unsorted, outgoing, 4 (Box 19)
    - Unsorted, incoming, 6 (Box 19)
    - Unsorted, incoming, 6 (Box 20)
    - Unsorted, incoming, 8 (Box 21)
  - Writings, 1893-1963, undated
    Contains drafts for novels, short stories, and essays, most autograph manuscript, unless otherwise identified, some with correspondence, clippings of reviews, or other related papers. Most writings are identified by literary genre; titles have not been verified, and some may be working titles. Other Writings include book reviews by McFee and introductions written by him for books by other authors, each roughly arranged alphabetically by title of book. Autograph manuscript diaries, 1911-1963, concern McFee's writing, as well as marine engineering work, ship voyages, and his family.
    The Printed Material subseries and scrapbooks in the Personal Papers subseries include additional clippings of reviews for McFee's writings. Additional clippings of writings by McFee are in scrapbooks in the Printed Material and Personal Papers subseries.
    Arranged alphabetically by title; followed by Other Writings arranged by genre; and unidentified writings.
    - "The Admirable Crichton" (article), 1943 July 6-8 (Box 22)
    - The Adopted (novel). Notes, [1951-1952] (Box 22)
    - "Alcoves of Memory." Typescript, 1929 April 30 (Box 22)
      Published in Library Review, Coatbridge, Scotland, 1930 spring
    - Aliens (novel). First draft, typescript, 1913 (Box 22)
    - "The Argument for Argosies" (article), no year August 27 (Box 22)
      Annotated: "For Nation's Business"
    - "As Well as I Can Remember" (article). Typescript, 1948 (Box 22)
      Reminiscences about living in Nutley, New Jersey
      Accompanied by: telegram from N. A. Troy to McFee, 1948 August 17
      Annotated: "This is for the Nutley Historical Society"
    - "Banana Growing in England" (article), undated (Box 22)
    - The Beachcomber (novel), 1935 March 20 (Box 22)
      Published by Doubleday, Doran (Garden City, N. Y., 1935)
    - The Beachcomber (novel). Typescript, revised, with printer's annotations, 1935; 3 (Box 22)
      "Revised April 26, Westport, Conn."
    - The Beachcomber (novel). Typescript, revised, with printer's annotations, 1935; 4 (Box 23)
    - "Bellissima!" (short story), undated (Box 23)
    - "Better Be Sure Than Sorry", 1941 May (Box 23)
      Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from McFee to James T. Babb, 1941 June
      Published in "This Week," New York Herald Tribune, 1941
      Accruals
      No Subnote Content
    - "Blue Eagle and Blue Peter" (article), 1933 August (Box 23)
      About the United States merchant marine
      Annotated: "H. T. Magazine, Aug 30, 1933"
    - Bones of Coral, 1954, undated; 2 (Box 23)
    - Bones of Coral, undated; 6 (Box 24)
    - Bones of Coral, undated; 8 (Box 25)
    - Bones of Coral, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Book of Old Ships" (article), 1924 December (Box 26)
      Gift of Francis W. Bronson, 1963
      About Henry Brundage Culver's The Book of Old Ships (Garden City, N. Y., 1924)
      Written for Doubleday, Page, and Co.
      Removed from The Book of Old Ships
    - "Books and Ships" (lecture), 1936 (Box 26)
      Speech given at the New York Book Fair, 1936 November 13
    - "Born to be Hanged" (essay). First draft, undated; 2 (Box 26)
      Working title: "The Narrowest Escape I Ever Had"
      Published in a limited edition, and later in More Harbours of Memory
    - "The Burlingtons: A Day in the Life of a Working Fictionist" (short story), 1919 September 9 (Box 26)
      Published in The Bookman, 1921 July
    - "The Cafe" (short story). Fragment, 1919 May 20 (Box 26)
    - "The Calculated Risk." Typescript, revised, 1958; 2 (Box 26)
      Accompanied by correspondence about publication
    - "Can You Hear Me?" (article) Autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1931 March 2 (Box 26)
      About McFee's deafness
      Annotated: "For Dr. Harold Hays, March 1931"
    - "The Captain Macedoine Cocktail." Printed, undated (Box 26)
    - Captain Macedoine's Daughter (novel). First draft, 1919 (Box 26)
    - Captain Macedoine's Daughter (novel).Typescript, undated (Box 26)
    - Captain Macedoine's Daughter (novel), undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - "Captain Musker's Love-Nest", 1932 July 20; 2 (Box 27)
      Accompanied by clippings
    - "The Captain of the Vestris" (essay), [1926] November 16 (Box 27)
      Originally titled "The Commodore of the Fleet"